Tuan-Wu CHEN

Email: tuanwuchen@gmail.com Website: https://bwaaah.github.io

PROFILE

A professional game developer with over 10 years of experience in the industry, specialized in developing technologies for gameplay, AI, and animation, and have contributed to the development of several successful AAA games such as Assassin's Creed, Back 4 Blood, Final Fantasy 7 Remake, God Eater 3, and Monster Hunter Stories. Speak Chinese, Japanese, and English, and have a beginner level proficiency in French.

EXPERIENCE

Ubisoft Quebec City, Quebec, Canada / Jun 2021 - Present (2 yrs 8 mos) Gameplay programmer

- Enhanced and implemented new features for Fight Systems and Animation Calibration Systems.
- Integrated and optimized codebases from prior projects for the Multiple Games Pipeline.
- Created rope physics simulations for chain weapon visuals and gameplay mechanics.
- Researched and prototyped unique features for Assassin's Creed codename Red. (C++)

TLM Partners Dover, Delaware, United States / Jan 2021 - Jun 2021 (6 mos)

Software Engineer

- Refined procedural animation systems, such as Turn in Place, Orientation Warping, Melee Twist, Focus Tracing, and Leg/Arm IK.
- Supported animators in setting up animation blueprints and assets in Unreal Engine.
- Resolved character death animation feedback delay issues caused by network latency.
- Shipped game: Back 4 Blood. (UE4, C++)

Square Enix Tokyo, Japan / Apr 2018 - Nov 2020 (2 yrs 8 mos)

Game Programmer

- Developed Synergy system that enables the companion NPC to instantly react to the player's actions, synchronizing animations, and providing support during combat.
- Developed the Companion Al system, incorporating Player Al for Classic mode, emphasizing a design that makes players feel in control of each party member through predictive Al support.
- Implemented combat gameplay features.
- Shipped game: Final Fantasy 7 Remake Intergrade, Final Fantasy 7 Remake. (UE4, C++)

Marvelous Tokyo, Japan / Apr 2016 - Mar 2018 (2 yrs)

Game Programmer

- Built a IK solver which handles procedural pose animation of human feet and multiple joint monster's limbs by implementing CCD IK algorithm, calculated foot placement, body posture, and blending.
- Implemented a data-driven AI system and gameplay features for AI characters.
- Enhanced the level design workflow by creating the Waypoint Auto-Generation Maya Plugin.
- Shipped game: God Eater 3, Monster Hunter Stories. (C++, Python, Mel)

Utagoe Tokyo, Japan / Aug 2013 - Mar 2016 (2 yrs 8 mos)

Game Programmer / Game Designer (Part-Time)

- Designed and balanced the game mechanisms and levels.
- Built the whole game from scratch by implementing both front-end and back-end systems.
- Developed web-based level design tools to Improve the iteration process.
- Shipped game: Cat Run. (Objective-C, PHP, JavaScript)

WebCrew Tokyo, Japan / Oct 2012 - Nov 2012 (2 mos)

Game Programmer (Internship)

- Implemented Network, 2D graphics, and User Interface features.
- Shipped game: Little Sheep Farm (Corona, Lua, PHP)

Arc System Works Tokyo, Japan / Sep 2012 (1 mos)

Game Programmer (Internship)

• Prototyping of a Tetris-like Nintendo 3DS game. (C++)

EDUCATION

Waseda University Tokyo, Japan / Apr 2010 - Mar 2014 Bachelor's degree, Computer Science and Engineering